# Monica Smith | Resume

Senior Interactive Designer Art Director I Project Manager

#### Contact

1 917 434 9789 www.monica-smith.com monica.smith.nyc@gmail.com

## **Profile**

Senior Interactive Designer / User Experience with ten years of experience. Proficient in CS4. Experienced in all phases of project development. Ability to engage with senior marketing, technical, and executive management. Supreme managerial and problem solving skills. A born organizer, team player, fun to work with, calm under pressure.

# **Areas of Expertise**

- Large, extended sites
- Editorial Layout
- E-commerce, sCommerce
- Micro sites
- Mobile sites
- · Writing style guides

- Information Architecture
- Desktop applications
- HTML, XHTML, CSS, CMS, PHP
- Motion graphics
- · Pitching clients
- · Project management

# **Professional Experience**

#### Design Consultant | Project Manager

1998 - current

- · Designed artist portfolios, real estate, wireless and iPhone apps.
- · Pitched flex applications & sCommerce user experiences
- Project management, planning, production of web sites.
- · Art Directed, produced, and casted photo shoots.

Client list: iXL, Serena Williams, AMC TV, André Balazs, AARP

## MLB.com | Senior Interactive Designer

2001 - 2008

- · Designed interface and layout for thirty pro baseball team sites.
- · Acted as design lead for music sites, e-com sites, editorial packages.
- · Implemented marketing solutions creatively, logically, and practically.
- Streamlined production process to facilitate multiple project deadlines.
- Partnered with other project leaders to lead teams of 25+ people.

Client list: MLB.com, SNY.tv, NYC.gov, EltonJohn.com, Arod.com

## Smallworld.com | Senior Visual Designer

2000

- Designed interfaces and layout for fantasy sports websites.
- · Managed intern program.
- Created visual marketing packages for sales pitches.
- · Produced banner ads, email blasts, and print promotions.

Client list: MLB.com, Sporting News, Doritos, Mercedes, Chevy.

## Memphis College of Art | Adjunct Professor

1997-1998

- Taught design software and principles, grad and undergrad level.
- · Implemented easy-to-understand concepts and hands on experience.
- Encouraged individuals to develop distinct visual style.
- Developed team projects to encourage authentic work experience.
- · Conducted motivational continuing education workshops.

#### Skills

Photoshop Illustrator After Effects Flash Dreamweaver Microsoft Office Suite

Editorial Layout E-commerce Interface Project Management UI & IA Logo Design

Photography Photo Retouching Illustration 2D Animation

Spanish

## **Education**

# Maryland Institute, College of Art Baltimore, MD

BFA - General Fine Arts 1990-1994

- Photography Concentration
- Printmaking
- Collage

## Memphis College of Art

Memphis, TN MFA - Computer Arts 1996-1998

- Web Design
- 3D Animation
- Digital Illustration
- Interactive Interface (Director)

#### **School of Visual Arts**

New York, NY Continuing Education 2006-2008

- Flash
- After Effects
- DVD Publishing

\*References available upon request